Guide to the Lysons Family Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Lysons family collection
1789-1964
OSB MSS 70
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
1.67
(4 boxes)
The collection consists of material gathered by Lindsay Fleming in the course of his research on the life and work of Samuel Lysons, and includes correspondence with scholars and Lyson family descendants; transcripts of portions of Lysons's diary and his letters to Hester Thrale Piozzi; the typsecript of Fleming's "Memoirs and Select Letters of Samuel Lysons"; photographs; and letters to and from Daniel and Samuel Lysons. The correspondence of Daniel Lysons mainly concerns his topographical studies; the correspondence of Samuel Lysons documents his antiquarian interests and his work as Keeper of the Records. Correspondents include William Coxe, Sir Thomas Lawrence, Thomas Penrose, and Wilfred Merton.
Fleming, Lindsay
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of James Marshall and Marie-Louise Osborn. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
DANIEL LYSONS, 1762-1834
Daniel Lysons was educated at Bath Grammar School and Oxford, receiving his B.A. in 1782 and his M.A. in 1785. In 1784, having taken orders, he became curate of Mortlake, becoming curate of Putney, Surrey, around 1790. While at Putney, Lysons began his survey of the area around London, in which he was encouraged by Horace Walpole, who appointed him as his chaplain. In 1804 he succeeded to the family living of Rodmarton, where he died in 1834.
Lysons's major work is The Environs of London, being an Historical Account of the Towns, Villages and Hamlets within twelve miles of that Capital (1792-1796). With his brother Samuel, Lysons began Magna Brittania, being a concise Topographical Account of the several Counties of Great Britain (1806-1822), but after the first six volumes, covering the counties from B to D, Samuel died and the project was discontinued. Daniel Lysons also contributed views and illustrations to other works and published several pamphlets on religious and historical subjects.
SAMUEL LYSONS, 1763-1819
Samuel Lysons was educated at Bath Grammar School and the Inner Temple, London. He was called to the bar in 1798, choosing the Oxford Circuit, and practiced law until December 1803, when he was appointed Keeper of the Records of the Tower of London. He was director of the F.S.A. from 1798-1809, elected Fellow of the Royal Society in 1797, and appointed vice-president and treasurer in 1810. He was appointed to the revived office of antiquary professor in the Royal Academy in 1818. Lysons died at Cirenchester in Gloucestershire in June of 1819.
Lysons engraved all 156 plates for Reliquae Britannico-Romanae (1801-1817), as well as the plates for Views and Antiquities of the County of Gloucestershire (1791) and A Collection of Gloucestershire Antiquities (1803). He published several other works, including "An Account of the Remains of a Roman Villa Discovered at Woodchester in the County of Gloucestershire" (1815).
Scope and Contents
The Lysons Family Collection consists of material collected by Lindsay Fleming in the course of research for his "Memoir and Select Letters of Samuel Lysons, V.P.R.S., V.P.S.A. 1763-1819" (Oxford, 1934). The papers span the dates 1789-1964, and have been organized into three series: I. Daniel and Samuel Lysons; II. Lysons Family Letters to Lindsay Fleming; III. Other Lindsay Fleming Papers.
Series I, Daniel and Samuel Lysons, is located in Boxes 1-2 and contains letters by and to both Lysons brothers, mostly concerning antiquities and their publications; copies of the correspondence of Samuel Lysons with Hester Lynch Piozzi and of portions of his diary; and other materials concerning his life in the hand of Lindsay Fleming.
Series II, Lysons Family Letters to Lindsay Fleming, is housed in Box 3 and consists of letters from various descendants of Daniel Lysons (1762-1834) to Lindsay Fleming in response to his research inquiries.
Series III, Other Lindsay Fleming Papers, is housed in Box 4 and contains Fleming's research correspondence with other scholars, including Roland Austin, R. W. Chapman, and Wilfred Merton; other research material, including a family tree of Lysons descendants; and auction catalogs related to sales of Lysons property, including the 1948 sale of Daniel Lysons's library.
Engravers -- Great Britain; Engraving -- Great Britain; Antiquarians -- Great Britain; Engravers -- Great Britain; Carlisle, Nicholas, 1771-1847; Coxe, William, 1747-1828; Fleming, Lindsay; Lawrence, Thomas, Sir, 1769-1830; Lysons, Daniel, 1762-1834; Lysons, Samuel, 1763-1819; Penrose, Thomas, 1742-1779; Great Britain. Public Record Office
- Daniel and Samuel Lysons, Series I
  - LYSONS, DANIEL, 1762-1834
    - ALS to Thomas Cadell; Rodmarton, 1823 Apr 14 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Scope and Contents
      4 p., with address.
      On financial details of the sale of
      his brother Samuel's Reliquae
      Britannico-Romanae, financial losses
      on his own Sermons; on Magna
      Britannia and other literary matters
  - LYSONS, DANIEL, 1762-1834
    - AL draft to unnamed recipient; no place, [1819 Aug?] (Box 1, Folder 2)
      1 p.
      Gratified by the appointment of
      Petrie to succeed his brother at the
      Tower of London
  - LYSONS, DANIEL, 1762-1834
    - Cheque for L45.9.0 payable to Ralph Price, esq., 1808 May 3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - LYSONS, DANIEL, 1762-1834
    - Memorandum on Samuel Lysons' first visit to the Royal Family in July, 1794 holograph (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Introduced by Sir Joseph Banks
  - LYSONS, DANIEL, 1762-1834
    - Portraits, etc., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - LYSONS, SAMUEL, 1763-1819
    - AL (draft) to [Charles Bragge-Bathurst] no place, [1804] (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Sends copy of his Gloucestershire
      Antiquities, which is about to be
      published. About the Master of the
      Rolls. Thanks him for his help in
      securing his new appointment as
      keeper of records in the Tower of
      London
  - LYSONS, SAMUEL, 1763-1819
    - ALS (draft) to [Edward Bray], K.N.W., 1810 Feb 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      2 p.
      About his gift to the BM of 2 vols.
      of mss relating to the County
      Palatine of Chester.
      Also about the need for a room to
      house Norman antiquities with a list
  - LYSONS, SAMUEL, 1763-1819
    - ALS (draft) to Edward Brooke, Rodmarton, 1811 Jul 14 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      3 p.
      Describes the excavation of the Roman
      mosaic pavement and hypocaust found
      on Brooke's property
  - LYSONS, SAMUEL, 1763-1819
    - ALS (draft) to F.J. Browne, Record Office, 1809 May 10 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      About a Dorsetshire mosaic pavement
      and its reproduction in a new edition
      of Hutchins' History and Antiquities
      of the County of Dorset
      With a letter from Browne to Lysons
  - LYSONS, SAMUEL, 1763-1819
    - AL (draft) to [Sir William Grant], 1752-1832, Master of the Rolls, n.p., 1804 Jan 21 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Thanks him for his help in securing
      Lysons' new appointment as keeper of
      the records in the Tower of London
  - LYSONS, SAMUEL, 1763-1819
    - ALS to the Revd. Sam Lysons [his father], Temple, 1797 Aug 11 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      3 p., with address
      Relates his visit to the Royal Family
      at Windsor to show them his book
  - LYSONS, SAMUEL, 1763-1819
    - 3 AL (drafts) to [Miss Planta], n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
      4 p.
      Asks her to thank Princess Elizabeth
      for a book sent by George III and for
      her efforts over the keepership of
      the Tower Records
      Also about a fall from a hackney
      coach and a mosaic pavement
  - LYSONS, SAMUEL, 1763-1819
    - 2 letters (copies) to an unnamed recipient, Temple and [? King's Bench Walk], 1796, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
      About delays in publication
      preventing his payment of debt to
      recipient and a dinner engagement
  - LYSONS, SAMUEL, 1763-1819
    - 3 letters (copies) to "My Ld", 1806, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 14)
      About Lysons and his brother planning
      visit to recipient to inspect his
      deeds
  - [?LYSONS, SAMUEL], 1763-1819
    - Drawing of the tomb of Daniel Lysons (an ancestor) in St. Mary-de-Crypt Church, Gloucester, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - [LYSONS, DANIEL], 1762-1834
    - "On the part taken by Thomas Lysons, Esqr., Mayor of Worcester in the events connected with Charles II": holograph [?], n.d. (Box 1, Folder 16)
      5 p.
  - LYSONS, SAMUEL, 1763-1819
    - AL (draft) to an unnamed recipient, Cirencester, 1812 Oct 19 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      About a seal which the recipient sent
      to Lysons for identification
  - [LYSONS, SAMUEL], 1763-1819
    - Inscription on the Lysons family memorial in the chancel of Hempstead Church, copy in Lysons' hand (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Names of his uncle, Daniel Lysons,
      and his wife probably added by Samuel
      Lysons
  - BATH, THOMAS THYNNE, 1ST MARQUIS OF, 1734-1796
    - ALS to Samuel Lysons, 1796 Aug 28 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      2 p., with address
      About mosaic patters for Lady
      Charlotte Bruce and the Queen
  - BLAKE, DR. W
    - ALS to Samuel Lysons, Taunton, 1810 Sep 17 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Describes in detail a Roman mosaic
      pavement, which Lysons may want to
      use in Reliquae Britannico-Romanae
  - BRAY, EDWARD
    - LS to Samuel Lysons, 1763-1819, 1810 Feb 10 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      1 p., with address
      Acknowledgement and thanks for his
      gift of manuscripts of the County
      Palatine of Chester and some Roman
      antiquities to the British Museum
  - BRAY, EDWARD
    - ALS to Samuels Lysons, British Museum, 1811 Jun 8 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      Acknowledges his gift of Roman
      antiquities to the Museum and his
      offer to help remove a mosaic
      pavement
  - BRAY, EDWARD
    - Memorandum of committee meeting of the trustees of the British Museum, signed copy, 1808 Mar 12 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      About Samuel Lysons' gift of a mosaic
      pavement to the BM and a possible
      gift of Roman antiquities if the
      museum appropriates a room for them
  - BROOKE, HENRY
    - 3 ALS to Samuel Lysons, Bristol (2) and London, 1810-11 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      5 p., with addresses
      With a pencil draft reply by Lysons
      About a Roman mosaic pavement found
      on his property and its removal
  - BROWN, W
    - 2 ALS to [?Samuel Lysons], Stonesfield, 1816 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      6 p.
      About the mosaic pavements at
      Stonesfield and Northleigh
  - BUTTERWORTH, JOSEPH, 1770-1826
    - ALS to Daniel Lysons, Trowbridge, 1819 Sep 2 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      On publishing Samuel Lysons'
      Proceedings in Chancery
  - CARLISLE, NICHOLAS, 1771-1847
    - ALS to Daniel Lysons, Somerset Place, 1821 Mar 13 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Franked by Manners-Sutton
      Gives Forster's epitaph with
      description of monument
  - COMERODE, GEORGE
    - ALS to Samuel Lyons, Harley St., [1812 or later] (Box 1, Folder 28)
      About the Horn of the Touders of
      Delamere, an engraving of which he
      wishes to publish in his History of
      the Hundred of Edisbury
  - COUNSELL, ANN
    - Receipt, holograph signed, for Hester and Priscilla Lysons, 1758 Oct 12 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - COXE, WILLIAM, 1747-1828
    - 3 ALS and 1 LS to Samuel Lysons, 1801-16, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 30)
      6 p., with addresses
      Suggests people to provide local
      information for Lysons' Reliquae
      Britannico-Romanae
      About his bad handwriting and a
      forgotten debt
  - [ELLIS, SIR HENRY], 1777-1869
    - Letter (copy) to Samuel Lysons, British Museum, 1815 Apr 7 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      About the Lanercost Book
  - GLOUCESTER, ENG.
    - "The Freeman's Oath": document on a printed form admitting Samuel Lysons to the freedom of the city, Gloucester, 1789 Jan 30 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - HOWARD, HENRY, 1769-1847
    - ALS to Samuel Lysons, Royal Academy, 1819 Jan 13 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      Informs him that he has been
      unanimously elected "Antiquarian to
      the Royal Academy."
  - LAWRENCE, SIR THOMAS 1769-1830
    - 3 ALS to Samuel Lysons, 1763-1819, no place, [1795 or later] (Box 1, Folder 34)
      10 p., various sizes
      About social engagements and the
      purchase of a picture of Lysons'
      father
  - LONGFORD, ELIZA
    - ALS to Doctor [?Daniel] Lysons, Cheltenham, 1764 Dec 19 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      Concerning the marriage settlement
      of William Frye to Mary Horne and the
      birth of their children
  - MACDONWAY, W.
    - ALS to Samuel Lysons, East Street, n.y. Aug 20 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      About a dispute in the parish of
      Mortlake
  - MATHIAS, THOMAS JAMES, 1754?-1835
    - ALS to the Rev. D[aniel] Lysons, 74 Monte d'Iddeo, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 37)
      Asks him to take copies of his
      Italian book to Mrs Starke in Rome
  - NICOLAY, FRANCIS
    - ALS to Daniel Lysons, Landgate, 1802 Sep 25 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      Inquires about a Saxon brass seal
      found at Hythe
  - PENNANT, DAVID, D. 1841
    - 2 ALS to Samuel Lysons, Great Cumberland and Downing, [1809], 1813 (Box 1, Folder 39)
      On a new edition of A Tour in Wales
      and his father's accuracy. Describes
      silver coin and asks its worth
      Lysons' note says it is counterfeit
  - PENROSE, THOMAS, 1770-1851
    - ALS to Daniel Lysons, Writtle, 1824 Apr 2 (Box 1, Folder 40)
      4 p., with address
      About his efforts to make Bandinel
      complete Samuel Lysons' Reliquae
      Britannico-Romanae, Lyson's impending
      trip to Italy, etc.
  - PENROSE, THOMAS, 1770-1851
    - ALS to D[aniel] Lysons, Kensington, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 41)
      Envies Lysons for his just completed
      trip to Italy
  - PLANTA, JOSEPH, 1744-1827
    - ALS to Samuel Lysons, Brit: Museum, 1797 Dec 27 (Box 1, Folder 42)
      Thanks for "your splendid present."
  - ROYAL SOCIETY OF LONDON
    - Notice to Samuel Lysons of his election to Fellowship, Royal Society, 1797 Feb 3 (Box 1, Folder 43)
      On an engraved form, signed by Sir
      Charles Blagden, Secretary
  - STOKES, ANTHONY I.
    - ALS to D[aniel] Lysons, Pembroke, 1818 Oct 27 (Box 1, Folder 44)
      About the boundary of Pembroke
  - STOKES, ANTHONY I.
    - ALS, to S. Lysons, Milford (Box 1, Folder 45)
      About Roman coins, which he has just
      sent to Lysons
  - WHEELER, JOHN
    - ALS to Samuel Lysons, Gloucester, 1816 Mar 4 (Box 1, Folder 46)
      Detailed description of a brick pipe
      found while digging the foundation of
      a new building
  - DIARY COPIES AND NOTES BY LINDSAY FLEMING
    - Materials for life of Samuel Lysons, Volume 1, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 47-51)
      Samuel Lysons and the Britsh Museum
    - Materials for life of Samuel Lysons, Volume 2, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 52-58)
      Includes information on his career,
      the Royal Family, and extracts from
      his diary, 1789-1800
      Also, notes in Fleming's hand from
      the Rolls of the reign of Richard II
    - Correspondence between Samuel Lysons (1763-1819) and Hester Lynch Piozzi (1741-1821) (Box 2, Folder 59-62)
      Photostats. With note from
      John M.C. Lysons
    - Small diary and notebook (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - "Memoirs and select letters of Samuel Lysons, V.P.R.S., V.P.S.A., (1763-1819) with descriptive catalogue...." (Box 2, Folder 64)
      "Foreword: How I became interested in
      Samuel Lysons." handwritten draft
    - Literary Productions of Samuel Lysons, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 65)
- Lysons Family Letters to Lindsay Fleming, Series II
  - LYSONS, A. GEORGINA
    - 4 ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1927-32 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - LYSONS, ANGELA
    - 2 ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1964 Oct, Nov (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - LYSONS, DANIEL
    - 7 ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1948 Jan-Jun (Box 3, Folder 68)
      - With: 1 TL (copy) from Fleming to Lysons, 1948 Jun 14
  - LYSONS, DANIEL G
    - 7 ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1925-26 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - 6 ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1926-27, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - 3 ALS (copies) to the Rev. D.G. Lysons from Lindsay Fleming, 1925-27 (Box 3, Folder 71)
      1 AL, incomplete copy from
      unidentified correspondent to the
      Rev. Lysons
  - LYSONS, MISS E.
    - TLS to Lindsay Fleming, TLS to the Oxford University Press, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - LYSONS, E.W.M.
    - 2 ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1931, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - LYSONS, ESME K.
    - 9 ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1926-48 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - 6 ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1948-49 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - 9 ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1949-53 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - 15 ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1955-58 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - 15 ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1958-61 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - 14 ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1961-64 (Box 3, Folder 79)
      With: 1 TLS (copy) to Miss Lysons
      from Lindsay Fleming, 1961 Feb 20
    - ALS, catalogue, and photograph concerning the sale of the portrait of Daniel Lysons, M.D. by Gainsborough (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - LYSONS, JOHN M.C.
    - 13 ALS, 1 TLS to Lindsay Fleming, 1955-61 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - 8 ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1962-65 (Box 3, Folder 82)
      With: 2 TL (copies) from Fleming
      to John M.C. Lysons, 1961
  - LYSONS, LORENZO A.C.
    - 3 ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - LYSONS, SAMUEL, D. 1953
    - ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1927 Jan 11 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - LYSONS, VICTORIA
    - 2 ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1926 Aug, Sep (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - LYSONS, W.L.G.
    - 6 ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1927-35 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - PATTINSON, TERESA (LYSONS)
    - 2 ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1928, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 87)
- Other Lindsay Fleming Papers, Series III
  - ASHMOLEAN MUSEUM, OXFORD
    - 2 ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1926 Aug 4-20 (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - BRITISH MUSEUM DEPT OF BRITISH AND MEDIAEVAL ANTIQUITIES
    - TLS, to Lindsay Fleming (Box 4, Folder 89)
  - GLOUCESTER, CITY LIBRARY
    - 2 ALS from Victor A. Woodman, 1 TLS from P.W. Bennett, 1950, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 90)
      With: V.A. Woodman, "Samuel Lysons,
      F.R.S.F.S.A., 1763-1819, from
      Gloucestershire Countryside"
  - HALES-TOOKE, J.E.T. AND SABIN, V. PHILIP
    - Letters on the Henry Bone miniature portraits of members of the Lysons family, 1959-61, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 91)
      2 TLS from Sabin, 1 TL (copy) from
      Sabin, and 1 ALS from Hales-Tooke,
      all to Lindsay Fleming
      1 clipping
  - SOCIETY OF ANTQUARIES OF LONDON
    - 2 ALS, 1 TLS to Lindsay Fleming, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 92)
      With: 1 receipt, signed, 1949
  - VICTORIA ART GALLERY AND MUNICIPAL LIBRARIES, BATH
    - 3 TLS and 1 printed receipt, signed, to Lindsay Fleming, 1956-60 (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - AUSTIN, ROLAND, 1874-1954
    - Approx. 60 letters and other material to Lindsay Fleming, 1926-64 (Box 4, Folder 94-98)
      With: AL (draft) in Fleming's hand to
      Austin Roland, 1944 Mar 10
      Other material as well
  - BRUTON, G.N.
    - 4 TLS, 1 ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1926-28 (Box 4, Folder 99)
  - CHAPMAN, ROBERT WILLIAM, 1881-1960
    - 1 ALS, 1 TLS to Lindsay Fleming, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 100)
  - COLTERELL, T.S.
    - 2 ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1925, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 101)
  - FARRAR, J.H.
    - 2 ALS, 1 TLS to Lindsay Fleming, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 102)
  - GRAY, IRVINE E. (GLOUCESTERSHIRE RECORDS OFFICE)
    - 2 TLS, 1 ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1962-64 (Box 4, Folder 103)
  - HERBERT, GEORGE
    - 2 ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 104)
  - HYDE, MARY CRAPO
    - 1 ALS, 1 TLS to Lindsay Fleming, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 105)
      With: 3 ALS from T.G. Millward to
      Lindsay Fleming, concerning 58
      letters from Hester Lynch
      (Salusbury) Thrale Piozzi to
      Samuel Lysons, 1930
  - JOHNSON, JOHN, 1882-1956
    - 3 TLS to Lindsay Fleming, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 106)
      With: Obituary of Johnson
  - JOHNSTONE, GEORGE H., CAPT.
    - 2 ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1928, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 107)
  - MERTON, WILFRED
    - 18 TLS, 1 ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1932-34 (Box 4, Folder 108)
      With: 3 TLS from Frank Kitton
  - PRICE, LEONARD C.
    - 2 ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1927 Apr 5-8 (Box 4, Folder 109)
    - 5 ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 110)
    - 5 ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1927-28 (Box 4, Folder 111)
  - REDSTONE, LILLIAN J.
    - ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1941 Dec 4 (Box 4, Folder 112)
  - ROBINSON, EDWARD
    - 2 TLS to Lindsay Fleming and 1 printed receipt, signed, 1951 Jun 5-29 (Box 4, Folder 113)
  - SOUTHESK, CHARLES NOEL CARNEGIE, 7TH EARL OF, 1854-1941
    - 3 ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1926 Sep-Oct (Box 4, Folder 114)
  - STIER, FRANCIS
    - TLS to Lindsay Fleming, Chichester, 1965 Mar 21 (Box 4, Folder 115)
  - WHILTOME, MARY H.
    - 3 ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1926 Jul-Sep (Box 4, Folder 116)
  - WINBOLT, S.E.
    - 5 ALS to Lindsay Fleming, 1926-28 (Box 4, Folder 117)
  - MISCELLANEOUS ALS TO LINDSAY FLEMING
    - 10 ALS from various people, 1925-48 (Box 4, Folder 118)
  - MISCELLANEOUS ALS AND TLS
    - From museums and dealers to Fleming, 1926-41 (Box 4, Folder 119)
  - MISCELLANEOUS NOTES
    - Notes in Fleming's hand (Box 4, Folder 120)
      "A catalogue of the valuable and
      extensive library of the late Samuel
      Lysons, esq., F.R.S. and F.A.S...."
      [A Lyson family tree], late 19th and
      early 20th C
      "Notes...on Hervey Morris"
      "Rough tracing of hatchment of Rev.
      Samuel Lysons 'discovered
      in 1954...'"
      Obituary of Major Daniel Lysons
  - CATALOGUES OF LYSONS MATERIAL
    - Book and Manuscript catalogues, 1932, n.d (Box 4, Folder 121)
    - Paintings and Furniture, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 122)
  - CATAOGUES: LYSONS, CANON [?SAMUEL]
    - Catalogue of Walpole letters auctioned by Sotheby, Wilkinson & Hodge, 1882 (copy), n.d. (Box 4, Folder 123)
  - CATALOGUES: LYSONS, DANIEL
    - Catalogue and correspondence concerning the sale of books and papers, owned by Daniel Lysons, at Sotheby's, 1948 Jun-Nov (Box 4, Folder 124)
  - LYSONS, SAMUEL, LITERARY PRODUCTIONS OF
    - Typescript, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 125-129)
  - MISCELLANEOUS RESEARCH MATERIAL
    - Photographs, portraits, clippings, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 130-133)